本字幕由✿花語&花丸字幕組✿共同製作
Launch!
上がれ
What was that?!
なんだ
It launched!
上がった
花火
The firework.
Where?
どこだ
遠い
It's far.
姫さん
Princess...
O maiden!
otome yo
Flare up in the dawning sun!
akatsuki ni moeagare
I want to tear off the guise of the ignorant
muchi de kayowaku mamorareru dake no
Frail protected princess and live
hime nugisutete watashi wa ikitai
To conquer the color of the burning dawn
mukashi yori sukoshi dake suki ni nareta
That I've recently started enjoying
akatsuki no sora no iro nabikase
With strength and commanding presence
rinzen to tsuyoku
I strive to be someone I'm proud of
kedakaku sora wo miagete
And looking up idealistically to the sky
hokoreru jibun ni narou
To protect, to love, to stand my ground
mamori aishi tsuranuku
I won't allow myself to lose anything again
keshite ubawasenai
Like a noble flower
kedakai hana no you ni
With single-minded passion
hitamuki na jounetsu de
Even if faced with a cruel fate
zankoku na sadame sae
I will push through
kirihiraite miseru kara
Episode 22:         The Night History Is Made
この女
You bitch!
お前も海賊の仲間か
Are you working with the pirates too?
あのガキと一緒に商品の中に紛れ込んでいやがったんだ
You and that kid slipped in with the other goods, didn't you?!
Then that firework...
じゃ さっきの花火は
They signaled this ship's location to their allies?
この船の場所を仲間に教えた
Is that what you did?!
そうなのか
Kill them quickly, before the rest come!
早く殺せ 奴らが来る前に
Don't!
やめろ
俺の腕でも首でも何でもやるから
You can take my arms or head, or anything else you want, but don't touch Yona-
ヨナは ヨナだけは
No!
やめろ
まったく君って子は
I can't believe you.
You actually did it.
本当に遣ってのけるとは
格好いいじゃないか
That was pretty cool.
ジェハ
Jae-ha!
お お前は
Y-You're the one who sank all those ships.
今まで数々の船を沈めたっていう
空舞う海賊
The flying pirate.
そんなことより むやみに近寄らない方がいい
That's not important right now.
You don't want to approach me carelessly.
殺してしまう
I'll kill you.
Huh?
彼女に危害を加えた君達に手加減できるほど
I'm not virtuous enough to go easy on the men who hurt her.
僕は聖人君子ではないからね
俺 生きてる
I'm alive?
やっぱりジェハは龍の力の持ち主だな
Jae-ha really does have the power of a dragon.
He's exceptionally strong.
強さが半端ない
And I'm... so powerless...
それに引き換え 俺は...
Yun? Yun!
ユン ユン
ヨナ
Yona?
Yun!
ユン
ヨナ 泣いてんの
Is Yona... crying?
俺のために
For me?
I cut the rope for you!
ヨナ
Yona...
たくさん殴られたのね
They really beat you up.
Yun!
ユン
よかった 生きてた
I'm so glad you're alive.
You're a mess yourself.
ヨナこそ ぼろぼろじゃんか
守れない
I can't protect her.
I can't protect Yona. I can't protect her!
俺じゃヨナを守れないよ
ユンのお蔭で成功したんだよ
You made the plan a success.
ユンはやっぱり 天才だね
You really are a genius!
I'm not a genius.
俺は天才なんかじゃない
すごいのは ヨナだよ
You're the one who's amazing.
やったね 俺達
We did it.
かかれ
Get them!
Mercenaries...
傭兵
Out of the way!
Yona!
ヨナちゃん
シンア
Sin-ha!
強い
He's strong.
シンアも来てくれたのね
Sin-ha, you came for us too!
I thought the Thunder Beast would come.
雷獣が来るかと思ってた
Hak's an important part of our force.
ハクは重要な戦力だからね
飛べる僕と夜目が利くシンア君がこっちに来たんだ
I came because I can jump,
and Sin-ha came because of his night vision.
花火
The firework.
どこだ
Where?!
遠い
It's far.
姫さん
Princess...
ジェハ
Jae-ha!
I know.
分かってる
緑龍 疲れてる
Green Dragon, you're tired.
まさか
No way.
女の子を抱いて飛ぶようには行かないだけさ
It just isn't like carrying a girl.
まぁ あの二人こそ 飛び出さんばかりの勢いで
こっちに来たいだろうけど
I'm sure those two would jump here if they could.
White Snake, why are you slowing down?
白蛇 なにだらだらやってんだ
Your movements have slowed as well.
そなたこそ 動きが鈍くなって居るぞ
まどろっこしいんだよ
It's a real pain,
殺さないようにするのも
not being able to kill them.
そうであろう そなたの野蛮の武器ではな
With your brutish weapon, I'm sure it is.
しかし 切りがねぇ
Anyway, there's no end to these guys.
落ち着かないのは分かるが
こっちに残ったんなら ちゃんと仕事しな
I know you're feeling restless, but if you're staying here, you'd better do your jobs.
If you slack off, I might miss.
ちんたらやってると手元が狂うよ 私の
やるな 婆さん
Not bad, old lady.
仲間で元気なのはもう お前らくらいなんだぞ
You're the only ones on our side
with any energy left!
船長殿が一番元気だ
No one has more energy than you, Captain.
相手の戦力は半分以上を削いだ
We've taken out more than half of their forces.
後はクムジを引きずり出すだけ
Now we just have to drag Kum-ji out of hiding.
この戦い クムジを叩けば終わる
Once we defeat Kum-ji, this battle ends!
それが出来たら
Then you'll be free to rescue that girl, or hit on her, whatever you want.
あの娘を助けるなり口説くなり 好きにしな
口説く
Hit on her?
Wh-What are you talking about?!
な 何を言っておる
我らは姫様の忠実なる僕
We are the princess's loyal servants!
それもいいかもな
That's not a bad idea.
Hak!
ハク
かかれ
Get them!
気合い入った
I'm fired up now.
ならぬぞ
You mustn't!
Go! Shove them back!
Jae-ha, are you all right?
ジェハ 無事か
後二隻沈めれば 俺達の勝ちだぜ
If we sink two more, we'll win!
Jae-ha!
ジェハ
Hey.
隣の船の傭兵に苦戦してるわね
The mercenaries on the ship
next to ours are resisting fiercely.
クムジはどこかしら
Where is Kum-ji?
商品の近くにいるのは間違いないよ
He must be near his merchandise.
Near?
近く
If he's not on this ship...
この船じゃないとすれば
あの船の傭兵の数 普通じゃない
That ship has far too many mercenaries.
クムジ様 傭兵部隊第四隊まで壊滅です
Lord Kum-ji, four companies of mercenaries have been annihilated.
海賊共も大半は動けないようですが
Most of the pirates are out of action, as well,
化け物のような奴等が次々と船を沈めて...
but those monsters keep sinking our ships.
商品も...
And the goods...
なんだ
What about them?
商品の船も海賊により占拠されつつあります
The pirates are about to capture
the ship carrying the goods.
そうか
I see.
小娘共を売るどころか
Not only did we fail to sell the girls,
人質にするのはできなかったというのだな
but we couldn't even use them as hostages.
はい
Yes, sir.
く 詳しいことは分かりませんが
I-I don't know the specifics,
but someone among the women
led the pirates to the ship.
商品の中の誰かが海賊共を手引きしたらしく
The attack hit came too quickly, without warning.
あっという間に襲撃を喰らったようで
商品の中
Among the women?
あの娘だ
It was that girl.
It's just a gut feeling...
確証はない
だがあの娘の存在が頭から離れん
but I can't stop thinking about her.
あの娘が何かしたに違いない
That girl must have done something.
こちらも傭兵を出しておりますが
We've sent mercenaries to the ship,
いくら出しても 化け物共の強さは切がなく
but there's no end to the strength
those monsters have.
持ち堪えているのは もはやこの船だけ
This is the only ship we still hold.
クムジ様
Lord Kum-ji, we should pull up the ladder bridge between the ships and retreat!
商品の船の渡り梯子を外し
ここを撤退をされた方が
You're telling me,
俺に
このヤンクムジに船を捨て 逃げろと言うのだな
Yan Kum-ji, to abandon my ship and flee?
It took me twenty years to become Lord of Awa.
阿波の領主となるまでに二十年
領主となって十年
Since I became the lord, it's been ten years.
三十年をかけ ここまで築き上げたものが
You think a group of pirates,
ばばが率いる海賊と たかが小娘に
led by an old woman and a little girl,
will destroy in one evening
what I spent thirty years building?
たった一晩で崩されるというのだが
F-Forgive me!
お お許しを
Ignore it. It's just a rat.
捨て置け 鼠だ
ジェハ シンア
Jae-ha! Sin-ha!
That's the ship!
その船だ
その船のどこかに クムジがいるはずだ
Kum-ji should be somewhere on that ship!
任せて
Leave it to us.
ヨナ 手伝って
Yona, help us.
ヨナ
Yona?
ジェハ
Jae-ha!
クムジはこの奥の隠し部屋にいるぜ
Kum-ji's back there, in a hidden room!
なんだ 僕が一番乗りじゃなかったの
Aw, man. I wasn't the first one to get here?
じゃ ここ任せたよ
I'll let you handle things here.
Sure thing!
クムジ 覚悟
Kum-ji, prepare yourself!
傭兵など 金でいくらでも雇える
I have money. I can always hire more mercenaries.
海賊共め
You damn pirates...
I'll go back to my estate, regroup my forces, and come back to tear you apart.
屋敷に戻って 態勢を立て直し
改めて八つ裂きにしてくれるわ
教えてやろう 船頭
Let me tell you something, Captain.
A truly powerful man is one who will use any dirty trick necessary,
真の権力者とは
あらゆる汚い手段を使い 恥を恐れず
我が身を守れる人間のことを言うのだ
without the slightest shame,
in order to protect himself.
このヤンクムジが生きている限り 戦は負けてはない
As long as I, Yan Kum-ji, am alive,
the battle is not lost.
海賊共は骨折り損の草臥れ儲けよ
Let the pirates waste their efforts.
部下を見捨てて逃げ出すとは 美しくないね
Abandoning your subordinates and fleeing is hardly beautiful!
クムジ様 奴が来ます
Lord Kum-ji, he's coming.
天かける龍と噂される男か
So you're the flying dragon I've heard about.
ちょうどいい
Perfect.
前から一度 撃ち落としてみたかったのよ
I've always wanted to shoot you down.
You're naive!
甘いわ
Well, flying dragon?
どうだ 天かける龍よ
海に落ちればもう飛べまい
You can't fly, now that you've fallen into the sea!
な なんだ この殺気は
Wh-What is this bloodlust I sense?
誰かが 俺を狙って
Someone is aiming for me.
どこだ
Where are they?
赤い...髪
Red hair?
なぜだ
Why?
なぜこんなに恐れを感じる
Why am I so afraid?
あんな小娘如きに
She's just a little girl.
Long ago, I once saw red hair
like yours at Hiryuu Castle.
一度だけ俺は
緋龍城にて
お前と同じ赤い髪を見たことがある
For just a moment, in the distance, I saw her hair reflecting the sun.
一瞬だけ
遠くから日の光に反射するその髪の女の名は
The girl was...
ヨナ姫
Princess Yona.
I see.
そうか
やはり
I knew it.
やはり...お前が...ヨナ姫
You are Princess Yona!
Father...
父上
船長 ギガン船長
Captain! Captain Gi-gan!
Kum-ji took an arrow and fell into the ocean!
クムジが矢を受けて 今海に
夜が明けたね
Dawn has broken.
So tired...
本当に終わったんだな
It's really over.
So tired...
お前ら このめでたい日に
Come on, guys. We should be celebrating.
でもそうだな
You're right, though.
We were fighting all night.
俺達一晩中戦ってたんだから
You're all a mess.
だらしないね
Are you going to sleep?
ねちまうのかい お前達
はい 船長
Yes, Captain.
But when you wake up,
you'll be ordinary fishermen.
目が覚めたら お前らは ただの漁師になっちまうのね
阿波に帰るよ
Let's go back to Awa.
Hey! Hey!
よかった
Thank goodness!
Princess, I'm glad you're all right.
姫様 よくご無事で
あんた達 見事にかすり傷一つないね
You guys don't have a single scratch on you.
可愛くない
I hate you.
But you two...
そいうお前等は
Upon closer inspection,
you're covered in bruises...
ARGH
Calm down, you rare beasts.
落ち着け 珍獣共
ARGH
You'll just cause more trouble.
めんどくさいから
ARGH
I had no idea all these people were fighting all night against Kum-ji.
こんなにたくさんの人たちは
一晩中クムジと戦ってくれていたなんて
Thank you.
ありがとうございました
君達を助けるのは当然のこと
Of course we rescued you.
Actually, I simply followed
my destiny to protect you.
いや 僕は君を守るという運命に従ったまでのこと
By the way, what's your name?
ところで君 名前は
ジェハ
Jae-ha!
Quit talking nonsense like it's second nature!
てめぇは空気を吸うように訳の分からんこと喋ってんじゃ...ねぇ
Yeah!
We did nothing to help you.
私達 何もできなくて
いいえ
No.
ユリは命懸けて 手を貸してくれたわ
You risked your life to help us.
Rina...
リナ
Yuri, my real name is... actually...
ユリ 私の名前は 本当は...
As long as people like you are around,
I'm sure Awa will be fine.
阿波はきっと大丈夫 ユリのような人がいれば
Thank you, Rina.
ありがとう リナ
それで あの
So, um...
皆さんに なにかお礼を
Is there some way we can thank you?
お礼だなんてそんな 俺達は...
Thank us? We don't need-
Pirates demand a pretty high price.
海賊が要求するお礼は高いよ
お前達と私等 この町全員で酔うための酒さ
Bring us all the liquor it will take
to get the entire town drunk.
All right!
よしゃ
Understood!
かしこまりました
なに言ってんの
What are you talking about?
みんなすごいけがだよ
Everyone is seriously injured.
We need to treat them first.
まず手当しなきゃ
Kid, get some snacks!
坊主 つまみ用意しろつまみ
What am I, your wife?
俺は嫁か
それより手当...
I need to treat them first-
バカ野郎
You idiot!
勝利の日は潰れるまで酒飲んで暴れるのが海賊の流儀だ
When they win, pirates drink and
party until they collapse.
It's still only morning!
まだ朝だよ
That sounds like fun.
激るね そいうの
乗るな 雷獣
Don't encourage them, Thunder Beast!
宴か 懐かしいな
A party? That brings back memories.
私の誕生祭では毎年龍の舞をみんなが踊ってくれたぞ
Every year on my birthday,
everyone would dance the dragon dance.
Where are the dancers and musicians?
舞子や奏者はどこだ
Huh?
I look forward to the music and plays.
歌とお芝居も楽しみね
Shut up, moneybags!
黙ってろ 金持ち
I'm hungry.
お腹すいた
プキュー シンアを食うな
Don't eat Sin-ha, squirrel!
仕方ないよ ユン君
They can't help it, Yun.
今日は特別だ
Today is special.
勝利 素晴らしいじゃないか
We won.
Isn't that splendid?
清らかで麗しい阿波の港と美少女達
The pure and beautiful Port of Awa
and its lovely young ladies...
そして今日という日を祝して美しいこの僕が
To celebrate this day, in all of my beauty,
脱ぐよ
I'll strip.
You're not playing a song?
曲じゃねぇのかよ
引っ込め変態
Get out of here, pervert!
Dribble Dribble Dribble
脱ぐよ
I'll take it all off.
Dribble Dribble Dribble
You're bleeding everywhere!
つぅか血出てんだよ思いっきり
Dribble Dribble Dribble
Just die already!
一遍滅べ
坊主 つまみはまだか
Kid, where are those snacks?
Get lost, idiot!
知らないよバカ
お待たせ
Thanks for waiting!
酒到着です
Your liquor has arrived!
静
It's quiet.
Last night's battle seems so far away.
さっきまでの戦いが遠い日の出来事みたい
I hope I did something to help
the people of this town.
少しは私 この町の人達の力になれたかな
父上
Father, have I become stronger?
少しは私 強くなれましたか
あまり遠くに来たら皆が心配する
If I go too far, everyone will worry.
戻らなきゃ
I'd better head back.
ご ごめんなさい
I-I'm sorry.
It's all right.
私こそ前方不注意で
I wasn't looking where I was going.
That voice...
Crying tears for the days that won't return
modoranai hibi ni namida koboshite
You look up to the sky, and it's burning bright red
miageta sora ga akaku akaku moeru
Now that you know your own strength and weakness
jibun no tsuyosa yowasa kizuketa no nara ima
You should have no fear and go where your heart takes you
kimi yo osoreruna kokoro omomuku mama
Cleaving through the wind, your path is lit
kaze wo kirisusumu sono tabiji wo
By the dawn
akatsuki ga terasu
(Gather, fierce arm)
(tsudoe takeki kaina)
(All-seeing eyes)
(senri no hitomi)
Feet that dash through the sky
sora wo kakeyuku ashi
(Shield of eternity)
(kuon no tate)
Fulfill the ancient vows
inishie no chikai ima hatashite
O night, break into dawn
yoru yo akete yuke
Next Time
今はまだ死ぬわけにはいかないんです
I cannot die yet.
私にはやるべきことがあるから
There's something I must do.
次回 暁のヨナ 第二十三話
Next time, Akatsuki no Yona, episode 23:
Episode 23:         Morning of Promise
誓いの朝
Morning of Promise.
The characters, groups, places, laws, and names used
in this program have no connection to any existing in real life.
This story is fiction.